Schaefer, Vincent; Papers ua902.010
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Atmospheric Sciences Research Center, 1950-1993; Undated; 6; 16.0 cubic ft.
  - Educational Activities, 1959-1992; Undated; 6.2
    Schaefer saw research opportunities via the ASRC that promised to have national and even international implications as environmental concerns became more public in the 1960s and 1970s. He was engaged frequently to speak about his research, both to other professionals and to "everyday" people who might be interested in learning more about issues like acid rain or solar energy. He also participated on committees and commissions who were given the responsibility of investigating scientific dilemmas of the day and presenting findings to the government. This subseries contains materials from those speaking engagements, trips, and committees.
    - Adventures Ahead, Undated (Box 4 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 1)
    - African Eclipse Cruise, 1972 (Box 4 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 2)
    - African Eclipse Cruise, 1973 (Box 4 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 3-9)
    - Ambassador College Research Department, Hippies, Hipocrisy [sic] and Happiness, Pasadena, California, 1968 (Box 4 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 10)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS), 1978 (Box 4 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 11)
    - ASRC Scrapbook: Schenectady Tornado, 1960 June 24 (Oversized 8)
    - Basic Studies in Experimental Meteorology Field Locations and Research Projects, Undated (Box 4 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 12)
    - Capitaland Natural Science Center-Tivlo Lakes Nature Study Sanctuary- Schaefer Award with citation and brochure, Undated (Box 4 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 13)
    - Carnahan(R.L), NOAA Industrial Meteorology News Clips, 1970 October 13 (Box 4 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 14)
    - Caumsett State Park, Long Island (Brochure, Notes, Correspondence), 1973 (Box 4 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 15)
    - Chancellor's Fellows (MSS), Undated (Box 4 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 16)
    - Chautauqua- Type Short Courses for College Teachers, 1973-1975 (Box 4 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 17)
    - Chautauqua- Type Short Courses for College Teachers, 1975-1976 (Box 4 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 18)
    - Chautauqua- Type Short Courses for College Teachers (application forms, correspondence, teachers materials, rosters of participants, maps), 1971-1972 (Box 4 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 19-20)
    - Chautauqua- Type Short Courses for College Teachers (application forms, schedules, timetables, grant forms), 1971-1972 (Box 4 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 21-23)
    - Chautauqua- Type Short Course Program, 1979 (Box 4 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 24)
    - Chautauqua- Type Short Courses for College, 1978 (Box 4 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 25)
    - Commission on Science Education, 1963-1966 (Box 4 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 26-28)
    - Commission on Science Education, 1963-1966 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 1-4)
    - Cooperative College- School Science Program Guide for Preparation of Proposals, Undated (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 5)
    - Cooperative United States of China Short Course Program for College and University Faculty Development Directory, 1979 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 6)
    - Dedicated Environmental Education for Posterity (DEEP), 1973 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 7)
    - Discovery Center of the Capital District (correspondence, proposal, mission statement), 1984 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 8)
    - Education: Leadership Programs, Undated (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 9)
    - Educational Monographs in the Atmospheric Sciences (American Meteorological Society), 1963-1965 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 10)
    - Environmental Education, 1971-1973 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 11)
    - Environmental Studies #1, 1970 September (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 12)
    - Environmental Studies Program, 1971 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 13)
    - Environmental Studies Program, 1971-1974 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 14)
    - Five Rivers Project: Outstanding Students, 1970 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 15)
    - Klinger Scientific Apparatus Corp., Experiments in Optics, Part 2, Bulletin 101-2, 1964 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 16)
    - Melander, Kathleen, Science Teacher (3rd & 4th grade letters and notebooks), 1954-1956 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 17)
    - Membership Cards, V.J. Schaefer, 1960-1961 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 18)
    - Mercy College, Dobbs Ferry, New York- A 1967-1968 Conference Series: Teacher Preparation in the New Industrial State (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 19)
    - National Science Foundation, 1964-1979 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 20)
    - National Science Teachers (notebook), Undated (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 21)
    - Natural Sciences Institute, Fredonia, 1964-1966 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 22)
    - Proposal for Reorientation, Undated (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 23)
    - Rochester Museum of Arts and Sciences, 1940-1967 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 24)
    - Schaefer Consulting, 1965-1968 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 25-26)
    - Schaefer Quiz to Graduate Students in the Atmospheric Sciences, Undated (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 27)
    - Schaefer V.J "A Formula for Happiness" (Notes used in giving commencement address at lake Pleasant Central School), Undated (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 28)
    - Schaefer V.J "A Program on Meteorological Research", Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute (Typescript, photograph, memorandum), 1959 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 29)
    - Schaefer, V.J and Mohnen, V., Atmospheric Science, Test Edition, AAAS Study Guides on Contemporary Problems- Part of the Chautauqua-Type Short Courses for College Teachers Program, Study Guide, 1974 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 30)
    - Schaefer V.J and Mohnen V.A, "The Sciences, Motions and Sinks of Trace Gases and Fine Particles in the Global Ecosystem", Course for Academic Credit(Syllabus), 1972 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 31)
    - Schaefer V.J, Chautauqua Short Course Lectures for Environmental Planning (Unpublished Typescript), 1972 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 32)
    - Schaefer V.J, "Factors Which Led to The Foundation of ASRC Thirty Years Ago (unpublished Mss.), 1991 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 33)
    - Schaefer V.J Final Report of the Natural Sciences Institute, 1966-1968 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 34)
    - Schaefer V.J "Meteorological Questions and Answers" prepared for the Hand of Wisdom game (typescript), Undated (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 35)
    - Schaefer V.J "Observation, Serendipity and Climatic Change, Journal of College Science Teaching 4.1 (pg. 19-22), 1974 September (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 36)
    - Schaefer V.J "Preliminary Draft of Proposal to National Science Foundation", Prepared by Vincent J. Schaefer for the radio Astronomy observatory, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute (typescript), 1959 February (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 37)
    - Schaefer V.J, Salkever L.R, and Widmer W.R, Multidisciplinary Program for Secondary School Teachers, The Research Foundation of State University of New York and State University of New York at Albany, 1973 October 12 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 38)
    - Schaefer V.J, The Early Days of ASRC, Undated (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 39)
    - Science Research Associates, Inc., 1963-1964 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 40-41)
    - Science Teaching (guides, notices, programs), 1953-1974 (Box 5 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 42-44)
    - Scientific Adventures (photographs, issues, adventure kits), Undated (Box 6 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 1)
    - Senior Science Seminar, 1960-1961 (Box 6 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 2)
    - Serendipity Hall, Undated (Box 6 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 3)
    - Simon's Rock Early College, 1972-1977 (Box 6 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 4)
    - Report, New York, NY, 1969 (Box 6 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 5)
    - State of New York Commission on Environmental Education, 1974 (Box 6 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 6)
    - State of New York Temporary State Commission on Youth Education in Conservation, 1970-1973 (Box 6 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 7-8)
    - SUNY- State Teachers College, Albany, New York Notebook, Undated (Box 6 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 9)
    - Student Science Training Program (Pre-college) for High-Ability Secondary School Students, Undated (Box 6 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 10)
    - Susquehanna Environmental Education association, 1974 (Box 6 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 11)
    - Talcott Mountain Science Center (brochures, plans, correspondence, reports, experiment possibilities), 1986 (Box 6 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 12)
    - Technical Glossary, Undated (Box 6 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 13)
    - The Experimental Earth Science Institute, Vestal, New York (correspondence), 1967 (Box 6 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 14)
    - Union College-G.E. Science Fellowship for Teachers, 1951 (Box 6 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 15)
    - University of Michigan (correspondence), 1970 (Box 7 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 1)
    - Volunteers in Technical Assistance (VITA), 1978 (Box 7 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 2-3)
    - Waterways '74 Project, 1974 (Box 7 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 4)
    - Whiteface Mountain Field Station Science Lectures Announcement, 1992 (Box 7 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 5)
  - General Research, 1950-1993; Undated; 6.3
    Although Schaefer had administrative duties as director of research, as well as overall director of the ASRC in later years, he still made as much time as possible for conducting his own research. In addition to experiments carried out in New York's Capital Region, he oversaw research at the Whiteface Mountain Field Station and Observatory as well as Flagstaff, Arizona, and led highly successful expeditions in the Yellowstone National Park. His fascination with particle studies continued during his ASRC years, leading to crucial investigations of carcinogens, acid rain, effects of particulate matter on global weather, aerosol studies, and much more. He also took great interest in alternative energy sources, solar energy specifically. Of course, cloud studies and ice-forming nuclei also remained a passion of Schaefer's. This subseries mainly consists of Schaefer's own investigations into those kinds of topics and offers a glimpse of his own notes, calculations, and observations on the subjects of interest to him.
    - Acid Rain, 1974-1984 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 1)
    - Aerosol Report, 1976-1977 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 2)
    - Aerosol Studies-Measurements and Notes, 1971-1976 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 3-6)
    - Aerosol Studies-Research Notebook, 1950-1971 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 7)
    - Air Pollution in the Household (Measurements, lists, pictures), 1971 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 8)
    - Air Pollution/Particle Studies, Undated (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 9-10)
    - Air Pollution/Particle Studies, Part II: Gases, Sources, Motions, and Sinks, Undated (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 11)
    - In the Adirondacks (Measurements, calculations and photos), 1974 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 12)
    - Air Quality in The Colorado Plateau Region (with notes and measurements), Undated (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 13)
    - Air Quality-Measurements and Research, Undated (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 14)
    - The Air Quality Patterns of Aerosols on the Global Scale Final Report 1976 (photos and measurements), 1972-1975 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 15)
    - The Air Quality Patterns of Aerosols on the Global Scale, Final Report (Measurements, charts, text, survey), 1974-1975 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 16)
    - The Air Quality Patterns of Aerosols on the Global Scale SUNYA, Final Report (notes, correspondence, measurements, budget), 1974-1976 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 17)
    - Aerosol Concentrations- Diurnal Variations, 1968-1969 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 18)
    - The Air Quality Patterns of Aerosols on the Global Scale, Final Report 1976 (summaries, measurements, charts), 1972-1976 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 19)
    - Air Quality Study, ca. 1978 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 20)
    - Aqua Kane, 1976 September (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 21)
    - Arapahoe Chemicals, Ferrocene: A Review of Published Evaluations as a Smoke Reducing Fuel Additive, 1971 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 22)
    - ASRC-SUNYA Global Network- (maps, charts, notes, and photos), 1971-1974 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 23)
    - Associated Press, "Ban on Fouling of Pure Air Upheld", with Schaefer Notes, 1972 November 03; Undated (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 24)
    - Average Aerosol Concentrations, North Atlantic,1966-1971, 1972 April 07 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 25)
    - B-Pinene Experiment, M. Landin, Whiteface Summit, 1972 June 10-1972 July 13 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 26-27)
    - Bechtel Project, 1974-1978 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 28)
    - Bell Telephone lab, New Jersey: Computer Model for Urban Areas, Undated (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 29)
    - Cahill(T.A) and Feeney(P.J) "Contribution of Freeway Traffic to Airborne Particulate Matter", Crocker Nuclear Laboratory, with Schaefer Notes, 1973 June 15 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 30)
    - Chicago: Particle studies, 1971 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 31)
    - Classic Hail Storm of the Great Plains, 1959 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 32-33)
    - Cloud Droplet Nuclei in the Polar Stratosphere, 1991 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 34)
    - Cloud Formations- Photo slides, 1967 (Box 8 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 35)
    - Cloud Seeding (T-Effect), 1971-1972 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 1)
    - The Cloud Water Project, 1984 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 2)
    - Colorado Watersheds- Reports and Correspondence, 1964 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 3)
    - Condensation Nuclei/Clean Global Air Study- Correspondence Travel Forms, Budget Data, Personnel, etc., 1971-1975 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 4-6)
    - Development of a RANNYS Program- Proposal by Volker Mohnen, 1974 February 25 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 7)
    - Droplet Size Comparisons- Diagram, Undated (Flat-file 9)
    - Effect of NO2 on Iodine/Ozone Reaction, Singlet Oxygen Notes, 1973 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 8)
    - Elemental Analysis of Rock Samples, 1981 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 9)
    - Energy Sources, 1972-1974 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 10)
    - Environmental one Corporation, Particle Studies, 1969-1974 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 11)
    - F.S. Meteor Expeditions, 1970-1978 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 12-13)
    - Field Notebook- Grand Canyon Expedition, 1975 September 22-1975 October 08 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 14)
    - Fiji Field Research Expedition, Undated (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 15)
    - Fiji Islands Trip (Measurements- Particle Studies), 1972 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 16)
    - Forest Fire Prevention and Suppression, 1961-1962 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 17)
    - Forest Fire Research/USDA TV Package-photos, Undated (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 18)
    - Forest influences and Cloud Seeding Evaluation, Rocky Mtn. Forest and Range Experiment Station, Undated (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 19)
    - Fujita- Moire Effect (Transparencies) (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 20)
    - Gardner Counter, Undated (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 21)
    - Gardner Associates- Fog Tubes, 1973 May (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 22)
    - General Electric Nuclei Studies-measurements, 1962-1963 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 23)
    - General Outline of a Proposal to Study Atmospheric Aerosols over a Wide Geographic Area, Undated (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 24)
    - Global Air Quality Surveys, 1970-1977 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 25)
    - Grand Canyon Chemistry Studies, with photos, 1975 November 20 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 26)
    - Grand Canyon-Snow Moon Photos, Undated (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 27)
    - Grand Canyon Expedition (measurements and photocopied pictures, maps and charts), 1975 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 28)
    - Hailstones and Water Molecules-Schaefer Research Notes, 1971 January 21; Undated (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 29)
    - Hailstorm Studies, ca. 1960 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 30)
    - Hawaii-Mac Farms, 1978 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 31)
    - Henderson, T.J- Ozone studies, Atmospheric Incorporated, 1974 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 32)
    - Hurricane Research, 1960; 1964 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 33)
    - Ice Crystals- photos and photo slides, 1967 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 34)
    - Ice-Embryo from Electric Charge, Undated (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 35)
    - Ideas for Desalinating Water, Undated (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 36)
    - Inadvertent Weather Modification: Jet Contrails (Photo slides), 1967 December 08 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 37)
    - Inadvertent Weather Modification Pollution- Includes Photo Slides, 1967 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 38)
    - Iodine Crystals and Exhaust Research, Undated (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 39)
    - Ireland, West Coast- Air Quality Studies, 1977 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 40)
    - Kalliroscope- Brochures, Reports and Photos, 1968-1976 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 41)
    - Kazima Dam Catchment Area- Maps, Undated (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 42)
    - Laboratory Notebook (Schaefer)-CN/CCN Project, 1983-1984 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 43)
    - Lake Effect Storms, 1964-1971 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 44-45)
    - Lake Powell Research Project, 1965; 1970; 1972; 1982; Undated (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 46)
    - Lake Powell Research Project, 1971-1975 (Box 9 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 47)
    - Lake Powell Research Project, 1972-1975 (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 1-4)
    - Lake Powell Research Project-Photos, Undated (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 5)
    - Large Airborne Particulates-Collection Methods, 1972 August 21 (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 6)
    - Locations of ASRC- SUNY Field Stations in New York State, 1975 September 15 (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 7)
    - Long Park Concept, 1971 (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 8)
    - Marble Lodge: Precipitation & Temperature measurements (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 9)
    - Megamex Project-Minutes of Meeting of Hydraulic Power Committee of P.A. Electric Association, 1952 April 22-1952 April 23 (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 10)
    - Megamex Project- Notes, Maps, and Correspondence, 1974-1975; Undated (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 11)
    - Memorandum on The Water Quality of New York State Surface Waters(unpublished typescripts with measurements), 1975 (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 12)
    - Mercury Pollution, 1971-1972 (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 13)
    - Mexican Research Expedition, 1967-1968 (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 14)
    - Millipore Corporation, Detection and Analysis of Particulate Contamination- Catalogue and Technical Brochure, 1966 (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 15)
    - Misty Rains and Air Pollution, 1966-1968 (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 16)
    - Monitory Stations- List, Undated (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 17)
    - M.T.I Aerosol Runs (Notes and Charts), 1978 (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 18)
    - Naquina Head ASRC Fog Facility- Photo Slides, 1966-1967 (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 19)
    - National Hurricane Research Laboratory Progress Report #43, 1964 November 15 (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 20)
    - The Navajo Project- Correspondence and Photos, 1971 (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 21)
    - Nimbus I Weather Satellite Photos (NASA), 1965 (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 22)
    - Notebooks- Miniature, 1960-1961 (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 23)
    - Notebooks- Miniature, 1962 (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 24)
    - Notebooks- Miniature, 1965-1967; Undated (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 25)
    - Notebooks-Miniature, Undated (Box 10 (6-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center), Folder 26)